# **Matthew Enyina**

Full stack engineer with 3+ years of experience developing web services. My most vital skills are Node.js and React.js. I'm very flexible in working with different technologies and methodologies, so I can quickly learn and adapt to new environments.

Ketu, Lagos State. +2348061313069 enyina3848@gmail.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Euidem I.T Solutions**, Lagos, Nigeria — Full Stack Engineer

August 2021 - PRESENT

Euidem I.T Solutions is a company that offers design and build services from initial idea to final execution. Worked with the backend team, focused on building APIs for a product suggestion service.

- Partnered with product managers, stakeholders, and designers to build new product offerings and tooling across the platform.
- Refactored 40% of legacy code to make the codebase cleaner and improved performance using newer React functionalities.
- Improved customer experience by implementing scheduling service appointments (pick up and drop offs)
- Improved analytics by tracking suggestion history
- Write efficient unit and integration tests.
- Review code Properly document API.

# **HOWMIES**, Nigeria — Backend Engineer

June 2020 - July 2021

HOWMIES is a start-up to provide affordable and easy-to-access housing services.

- Worked with five engineers in building a property listing system (similar to Airbnb).
- Developed Web API backend using Node.js, Express.js, and JWT for user authentication.
- Used Netlify for hosting.
- Integrated with Nodemailer for email and SMS notifications.
- Write efficient unit and integration tests.
- Review code.
- Document API.

# **Freelance**, Nigeria — Full-stack Engineer

From January 2020

Real-Time Chat App

• Developed a chat app with rooms using Nodejs, Express, and

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript

TypeScript

Node.js

Nest.js

React.js

Next.js

MongoDB

PostgreSQL

MySQL

## **TESTS**

Jest

#### **TOOLS**

Git/GitHub/Gitlab

Postman

Docker

#### **CLOUD SERVICES**

**AWS** 

Heroku

#### **LINKS**

Personal Portfolio

**GitHub** 

**LinkedIn** 

Socket.io.

• Implement a real-time chat system with different rooms

#### **HItours**

- Developed REST APIs for a tourist site using Node.js, Express.js, and JWT for user authentication.
- Integrated with Nodemailer for email and SMS notifications.
- Used MongoDB for data storage.
- Jest for unit testing

## SHOP@KEGO

- Developed a full-stack e-commerce application with an admin layout using React.js, Redux, Node.js, and Express.js.
- Designed database schema used for the backend.
- JWT for authentication service that handles auth for both the main app and an admin app.
- Stripe for payments.
- Heroku for hosting

## **PROJECTS**

**Shop@Kego** — An e-commerce shopping app.

React App (shop-kego.herokuapp.com)

**Tour App** — An app for tourists to find and book the best destination for their intended tour with information to help them get that first-class vacation.

Envina/Hitours: Tour booking app (github.com)

### **EDUCATION**

# Skillup Africa, Lagos — Backend Engineer

From August 2021 - February 2022

**Niger Delta University,** Wilberforce Island Bayelsa — *B.Eng. Marine Engineering* 

From September 2014 - June 2020

#### **LANGUAGES**

English - Fluent.